Ciaran Toner

Full-Stack Developer

Summary

Front-end web developer with 3 years experience with a working knowledge of full-stack web applications. Adept at contributing to a highly collaborative work environment, finding solutions to optimise workflow & improve application performance without compromising on code quality and maintainability.

Experience

Web developer: Love Nature | June 2021- Nov 2022

Redesigned online store, and implement best security practices. This included updating store products, pricing, product descriptions & checkout flow.

Manager: Nourish Health Store | Jan 2019 - Mar 2020

Responsible for overall performance and running of the store & ensured a culture of excellent customer service was maintained. Lead a highly effective team of 6 in day-to-day operations in a motivating way while maintaining high store standards of cleanliness, merchandising, and compliance with health & safety.

Managing director: Natural Living Health Store | Jan 2017 - Dec 2018

As the owner and manager of the business, I was responsible for building and maintaining a successful business which included the day-to-day running of the store. This comprised customer service & sales, developing and running of the online store, stock management & accounting. As a sole entrepreneur, I ran a successful business for two years which assisted me with learning many aspects of business management, customer & business relations & many other invaluable insights gained.

Education

Current studies

Full stack software development with Code Institute

Certificates

Udemy - The Complete JavaScript Course 2023 (69 hours) Udemy - Node.js, Express, MongoDB (42 hours) Matering Nuxt (10 hours)

Dublin Institute of Technology, Dublin - Diet, Nutrition & Disease 2012

Contact

+353851010043

ciaran toner@icloud.com

ciaran-io.dev

github.com/ciaran-io

in linkedin.com/in/ciaran-toner

Skills

Languages

JavaScript, TypeScript, Python HTML, CSS

Databases

MobgoDB, Firebase, MySQL, Postgres

Technologies

Vue.js, NuxtJS, Node.js, Linux, Command Line, Netlify, Tailwindcss, Cloudflare, Meilisearch, Algolia, Express.js. Django, GitHub

Tools

VSCode, PyCharm Figma, Git, Linear, Postman, Affinity Photo, web developer tools